Guide to the Justin R. Hartzog papers,1917-1966.
Hartzog, Justin R. papers,1917-1966.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Justin R. Hartzog papers, 1917-1966.
2407
Justin R.(Justin Richardson), Hartzog 1892-1963.
38.5 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Maps/Charts, Newspapers, Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, reports, blueprints, whiteprints, maps, pamphlets, monographs, and newspaper clippings mainly concerning his association (1922-1937) with John Nolen.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
City planner.
Justin R. Hartzog graduated from Cornell University in 1917, and in 1922 received a Masters Degree in Landscape Design from Cornell.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, reports, blueprints, whiteprints, maps, pamphlets, monographs, and newspaper clippings mainly concerning his association (1922-1937) with John Nolen, the city planner of Cambridge, Massachusetts, and his own consulting practice in Cambridge and Fayetteville, Ohio, on projects at Dubuque, Iowa; Little Rock, Arkansas; Roanoke, Virginia; Lancaster, Pennsylvania; Columbus, Georgia; Elizabethton, Tennessee; San Antonio, Texas; Milton, Massachusetts; and elsewhere; his chairmanship of the Massachusetts Federation of Planning Boards and the Cambridge Planning Board; his state planning activities as consultant from the National Resources Planning Board for New Hampshire and Rhode Island, for the Maine State Planning Board, and the New England Regional Planning Commission; and his consulting work for agencies of the federal government, including the U.S. Housing Authority (1935-42), the Division of Defense Housing Coordination for the New England Region (1940-41), the Division of Urban Studies of the National Housing Agency (1942-44), and the Resettlement Administration for Greenhills, Ohio, where he was chief town planner (1935-37) and consultant after its sale by the government (1947-63).
Also included are letters, reports, notes, and other papers concerning his studies at Cornell University; his active and reserve service with the U.S. Army (1917-41); lectures he gave at Cornell University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Harvard University, and Ohio State University; and his activities in professional organizations, in particular the American Society of Civil Engineers and the American Society of Landscape Architects. Also, briefs and depositions (1960-66) in the Greenhills Home Owners Corporation suit. The major correspondents are Jacob Crane Sr., John Nolen, Sr., and Bradford Williams; there are also occasional letters from Frederick Adams, Tracy B. Augur, Harland Bartholomew, Frederick Bigger, Arthur Comey, Earle S. Draper, Charles Eliot, Carl Feiss, Harold Lewis, Benton MacKaye, Howard K. Menhinick, Paul Oppermann, Ladislas Segoe, Clarence S. Stein, and Raymond Unwin.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hartzog, Justin R.1892-1963.; Adams, Frederick.; Augur, Tracy Baldwin, 1896-1974.; Bartholomew, Harland.; Bigger, Fredrick.; Comey, Arthur.; Crane, Jacob L.(Jacob Leslie), 1892-1988.; Draper, Earle Sumner, 1893-; Eliot, Charles.; Feiss, Carl M.; Lewis, Harold MacLean, 1889-; MacKaye, Benton, 1879-; Menhinick, Howard K.; Nolen, John, 1869-1937.; Oppermann, Paul, 1903-1977.; Segoe, Ladislas.; Stein, Clarence S.; Unwin, Raymond, 1863-1940.; Williams, Bradford.; American Society of Civil Engineers.; American Society of Landscape Architects.; Cambridge (Mass.).Planning Board.; Cornell University--Students.; Greenhills Home Owners Corporation.; Maine.State Planning Board.; Massachusetts Federation of Planning Boards.; New England Regional Planning Commission.; United States.Division of Defense Housing Coordination for the New England Region.; United States.National Housing Agency.Division of Urban Studies.; United States.National Resources Planning Board.; United States.Resettlement Administration.
Subjects:
City planning.; Housing.; Regional planning.; City planners.
Places:
Cambridge (Mass.)--City planning.; Columbus (Ga.)--City planning.; Dubuque (Iowa)--City planning.; Elizabethton (Tenn.)--City planning.; Fayetteville (Ohio)--City planning.; Greenhills (Ohio)--City planning.; Lancaster (Pa.)--City planning.; Little Rock (Ark.)--City planning.; Milton (Mass.)--City planning.; Roanoke (Va.)--City planning.; San Antonio (Tex.)--City planning.
Form and Genre Terms:
Blueprints.; Maps.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
John Nolan papers, #2903.
CONTAINER LIST
- Link to a copy of the printed finding aid. Searchable PDF.
  Not all the material in the collection is covered by this guide.
- Biographical Materials
  - Personal material (Box 2)
    Photograph, greeting cards, announcements, invitations, etc.
  - Professional record (Box 2)
  - Denison University, 1934 (Box 2)
    Alumni appeal
  - Cornell University, 1917 (Box 2)
    Pamphlets and class notes
  - Pen and ink drawings (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 2)
    Relating to Hartzog, his father and miscellaneous
  - Speeches and papers (Box 2)
  - Working papers (Box 2)
  - Military career, 1917-1941 (Box 2)
    In QMS Reserves, 1920-1941
  - Cambridge School of Architecture and Landscape Architecture, 1932-1935 (Box 2)
    Thesis critic
  - Harvard lectures, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Harvard discussion, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Cornell lecture, 1933 (Box 2)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology seminars, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, visiting critic and Associate Professor, 1938-1943 (Box 2)
  - Ohio State University Judge, 1928 (Box 2)
  - lecture, 1953 (Box 2)
- Correspondence
  - Aerial Mapping (Box 2)
  - Aerial Surveys Incorporated (Box 2)
  - Airports (Box 2)
  - American City Planning Institute (Box 2)
  - American Civic Association (Box 2)
  - American Electric Railway Association (Box 2)
  - American Federation of Arts (Box 2)
  - American Institute of Architects (Box 2)
  - American Institute of Planners (Box 2)
  - American Planning and Civic Association (Box 2)
  - American Road Builders Association (Box 2)
  - American Society of Civil Engineers (Box 2)
  - American Society of Landscape Architects (Box 3)
  - American Society of Planning Officials (Box 3)
  - Andrew, F.M. (Box 3)
  - Arnold, E. (Box 3)
  - Avon Hill Association (Box 3)
  - Bemis, A.F. (Box 3)
  - Boston Society of Landscape Architects (Box 3)
  - Brookline Massachusetts, Town of (Box 3)
  - Charlotte North Carolina - Jones, Edwin L. (Box 3)
  - Chelsea, Massachusetts (Box 3)
  - Contest - municipal airport design (Box 3)
  - Contreras, C. (Box 3)
  - Cook, W.D. (Box 3)
  - Denver Planning Commission (Box 3)
  - Doten, Dana (Box 3)
  - Emergency Discussion and Unemployment (Box 3)
  - Employment, Applications for (Box 3)
  - Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences (Box 3)
  - European Cities (Box 3)
  - F Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Fairfax Hotel (Box 3)
  - Gordon-Dawson Company (Box 3)
  - Hapton, N.H. (Box 3)
  - Harkness, Albert (Box 3)
  - High Point, North Carolina (Box 3)
  - Hills Estate - Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 3)
  - Housing Association of Metropolitan Boston (Box 3)
  - Housing and Home Finance Agency (Box 3)
  - Hsinking, Hanchoukuo (Box 3)
  - Interprofessional Urban Planning Commission (Box 3)
  - J Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - K Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Kansas City (Box 3)
  - Kentucky Project (Box 3)
  - L Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Le Feber, Albert (Box 3)
  - Long Island State Park Commission (Box 3)
  - M Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - MacNaughton, P. John (Box 3)
  - Massachusetts Real Estate Exchange (Box 3)
  - Middle River, Maryland (Box 3)
    The Glenn L. Martin Company - Robert L. Henry
  - Millar's Housing letter (Box 3)
  - National Bureau of Casualty and Surety Underwriters (Box 3)
  - National Commission on the Housing Emergency Incorporated (Box 3)
  - National Land Use Planning Commission (Box 3)
  - National Public Housing Conference (Box 3)
  - New England Council (Box 3)
  - New York, Plan for its Environs (Box 3)
  - P Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Parsons, Charlotte G. (Box 3)
  - Rotary Club (Box 3)
  - Rural Electrification Administration (Box 3)
  - Rural Land Planning (Box 3)
  - S Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Schenectady Bureau of Municipal Research (Box 3)
  - South Kingson, Rhode Island (Box 3)
  - Standard Oil Company (Box 3)
  - State Housing Bills (Box 3)
  - Stephens, George (Box 3)
  - T Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Taylor, A.D. (Box 3)
  - Tucker, L.H. (Box 3)
  - Veterans Administration (Box 3)
  - W Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Welyn Garden City, England (Box 3)
  - Williams, Leslie (Box 3)
  - Wilmington, North Carolina (Box 3)
- Career with John Nolan
  1922-1926: Technical Assistant in town planning and subdivision. 1926-1937: Associate in practice of town and regional planning
  - Administrative files
    - Correspondence and working papers, 1925-1931 (Box 4)
    - 2 Notebooks on Parkways research, 1932-1933 (Box 4)
  - Reports and Plans
    - Ashville, North Carolina (Box 4)
    - Atlantic City, New Jersey (Box 4)
    - Binghamton, New York (Box 4)
    - Charleston, South Carolina (Box 4)
    - Chicago, Illinois (Box 4)
    - Connecticut State Planning Board (Box 4)
    - Marimont, Ohio (Box 4)
    - Maryland property (Box 4)
    - Minnesota (Box 4)
    - New England (Box 4)
    - Niagara Falls, New York (Box 4)
    - Riverton, New Jersey (Box 4)
    - San Diego, California (Box 4)
    - Selkirk Shores (Box 4)
    - Spartansburg, South Carolina (Box 4)
    - Subsistence Homestead Data (Box 4)
    - Wheeling, West Virginia (Box 4)
    - Wilmington, Delaware (Box 4)
    - Winchester, Connecticut (Box 4)
  - Outlines
    - Replanning of existing cities (Box 4)
    - Regional plan (Box 4)
    - New Town site planning (Box 4)
    - Land subdivision (Box 4)
    - Consulting and planning services (Box 4)
  - Forms and tables
    - Contract forms (Box 4)
    - Specifications and Questionnaires (Box 4)
    - Table of scales (Box 4)
- Projects
  - Pennsylvania
    - General manuscripts, 1934 (Box 5)
    - Reports
      - Erie (Box 5)
      - Harrisburg (Box 5)
      - Lancaster (Box 5)
      - Lower Merion (Box 5)
      - McKaesport (Box 5)
      - Philadelphia - Tri-State Area District (Box 5)
      - Reading (Wyomissing Park) - includes 3 boxes of aerial surveys) (Box 5)
      - Sharon (Box 5)
  - Iowa
    - Dubuque
      - Estimate for city planning, 1930 (Box 6)
      - Report on Major Streets and Highways, December, 1930 (Box 6)
      - Proposed Zoning Ordinance, June, 1932 (Box 6)
      - Photograph of plans, 1938 (Box 6)
      - Dubuque Report, 1948 (Box 6)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1947-1948 (Box 6)
      - Dubuque Master plan, 1949 (Box 6)
      - Reports and statements, 1951 (Box 6)
      - Dubuque Planning and Zoning Commission Minutes, 1948-1951 (Box 6)
      - Master plan, 1951 (Box 6)
      - Preliminary report - Revision of the 1934 Ordinance, January 1952 (Box 6)
      - Dock Commission - Industrial Park, Peosta Highway, 1956 (Box 6)
      - Report on expansion of the city area, 1952 (Box 6)
      - Revision of Ordinance #23-45, 1954-1957 (Box 6)
      - Planning data, January, 1958 (Box 6)
      - Extension of master plan, 1958 (Box 6)
      - Land use and zoning study, 1958 (Box 6)
      - Chamber of Commerce Urban Development Commission, 1958 (Box 6)
      - Dove, C.E. - Mississippi Valley Parkway, 1958-1959 (Box 6)
      - First Baptist Church, 1959 (Box 6)
      - Urban Renewal Investigation, 1959 (Box 6)
      - Urban Renewal Workable Plan, November 1959 (Box 6)
      - News Reports (Box 6)
      - Visit, October 9-15, 1960 (Box 6)
      - Traffic Forecast - Iowa State Highway Commission, 1959-1960 (Box 6)
      - Dovon Drive Problem, 1960 (Box 6)
      - On-Street Parking Study, 1960 (Box 6)
      - Revision of Zoning Regulations - Residential Districts, 1960 (Box 6)
      - Shopping Centers, 1960 (Box 6)
      - Old Timers Road Extension (South), 1960-1961 (Box 6)
      - Visit, May 7-13, 1961 (Box 6)
      - Annexation (proposed) News Items, 1961 (Box 6)
      - Report on Urban Renewal, 1961 (Box 6)
      - University of Dubuque, 1961 (Box 6)
      - Data Planning, 1961-1962 (Box 6)
      - Water Department, March 1962 (Box 6)
      - Cultural Center, April 1962 (Box 6)
      - Radion Editorial, 1962 (Box 6)
      - Printed Material (Box 6)
        Ordinances, plat books, pamphlets
    - Sioux City, 1930 (Box 6)
  - Florida
    - Belleair (Box 7)
      2 pamphlets
    - Bellmont-on-the-Gulf (Box 7)
      plan
    - Clearwater, 1925 (Box 7)
    - Coral Gables (Box 7)
      Pamphlets
    - Fort Myers-Tamiami City (Box 7)
    - Lake Wales, 1926 (Box 7)
    - Sarasota, 1925 (Box 7)
    - St. Petersburg, 1926-1927 (Box 7)
      Manuscripts regarding zoning and planning, newspaper clippings, pamphlets and aerial surveys
    - Venice, 1925-1926 (Box 7)
    - West Palm Beach, 1923 (Box 7)
  - Little Rock, Arkansas
    1928-1930: Prepared City Plan. 1931: Prepared plan for Allsopp Park in Little Rock. 1933: Zoning Act
    - Correspondence, 1928-1932 (Box 7)
    - Personnel (Box 7)
    - Schedule (Box 7)
    - Finances (Box 7)
    - Survey (Box 7)
    - Legal (Box 7)
    - Arkansas-Texas (Box 7)
    - General (Box 7)
    - Reports, 1928-1930 (Box 7)
    - Manuscripts for City Plan (Box 7)
    - Report to accompany preliminary plans (Box 7)
    - Comprehensive City Plan, 1929 (Box 7)
    - Allsopp Park, 1931 (Box 7)
    - Zoning Act, 1933 (Box 7)
    - Newspaper clippings and drawings (Box 7)
    - City Plan, 1930 (Box 7)
  - Roanoke, Virginia
    1927: Reconnaissance Survey and Planning Report. 1928: Zoning Ordinances, street plans, city planning report. 1931: Long Term Financial Program for Public Improvements and Report.
    - State Planning Board report, 1934 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1939 (Box 8)
    - Personnel (Box 8)
    - Reports (Box 8)
    - Contract (Box 8)
    - Schedule (Box 8)
    - Finances (Box 8)
    - Survey (Box 8)
    - Legal (Box 8)
    - General manuscripts (Box 8)
    - Zoning Ordinance, 1928 (Box 8)
    - Airport, 1928 (Box 8)
    - City Plan, 1928 (Box 8)
    - Report on Long Term Budget Program, 1931 (Box 8)
    - Charter, 1924 (Box 8)
    - Annual Reports, 1927, 1929, 1930 (Box 8)
    - Comprehensive City Plan, 1928 (Box 8)
      Leather bound
    - Newport News, 1930 (Box 8)
    - Mount Vernon Memorial Highway (Box 8)
      Photographs and pamphlet
  - Columbus, Georgia
    - Working papers and city plan, 1923-1926 (Box 8)
  - Tennessee
    - Elizabethtown-Johnson City, 1927 (Box 8)
      American Glanzhoff Corporation - Happy Valley development
    - Tennessee Valley Authority
      Hertzog applied for a job as town planner, was offered it, and turned it down.
      - Correspondence, 1933-1942 (Box 8)
      - Bulletins (Box 8)
      - Lecture by Earle S. Draper, Director, Division of Planning and Housing (Box 8)
  - San Antonio, Texas
    1935: Designed a pleasure and health resort for the Hoblitzelle Holding Corporation.
    - Personnel, c. 1935 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, c. 1935 (Box 8)
    - Reports, c. 1935 (Box 8)
    - Agreements, c. 1935 (Box 8)
    - Procedure, c. 1935 (Box 8)
    - Program, c. 1935 (Box 8)
    - Reference Data, c. 1935 (Box 8)
    - Estimates, c. 1935 (Box 8)
    - Hoblitzelle, Karl, c. 1935 (Box 8)
    - Material for pamphlet, c. 1935 (Box 8)
  - Massachusetts
    - Massachusetts Federation of Planning Boards
      1950-1952: Chairman
      - Correspondence (Box 9)
      - Conferences, 1938-1951 (Box 9)
        Also contains correspondence.
      - Constitution, 1946-1949 (Box 9)
      - Executive Committee, 1946-1949 (Box 9)
      - Directors, 1946-1949 (Box 9)
      - Annual Meetings, 1946-1949 (Box 9)
      - Publications, 1946-1949 (Box 9)
      - Regional Activities Committee, 1946-1949 (Box 9)
      - Regions, 1946-1949 (Box 9)
      - Legislation, 1946-1949 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1946-1949 (Box 9)
      - Chairman, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Vice-Chairman, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Treasurer, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Secretary, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Constitution, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Executive Committee, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Board of Directors, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Annual Meeting, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Publications, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Regional Activities Committee, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Regions, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Legislation, 1949-1951 (Box 9)
      - Working papers (Box 9)
      - Treasurer's reports (Box 9)
      - Place names for Massachusetts (Box 9)
      - Conservation (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous printed materials (Box 9)
    - Milton Planning Board
      1950-1953: Town Planning Consultant
      - Correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box 10)
      - Minutes of meetings (Box 10)
      - Fire Station (Box 10)
      - Subdivision (Box 10)
      - Zoning (Box 10)
      - Report on Increase of Minimum Lot Area and Frontage - C District, 1951 (Box 10)
      - Report on Potentialities of Development - Houghton's Pond Area, 1952 (Box 10)
      - Report on Long Term Residential Zoning Needs in Milton, 1952 (Box 10)
      - Newspapers clippings (Box 10)
      - Pamphlets (Box 10)
      - Annual Reports, 1949-1952 (Box 10)
    - Boston
      - General and detail layout plans for proposed housing projects, 1933 (Box 10)
      - Housing, 1933-1935 (Box 10)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 10)
      - Park Department contracts, 1911 (Box 10)
      - Outline maps (Box 10)
    - Other Cities in Massachusetts
      - East Wapole (Box 10)
      - Edgartown, 1951 (Box 10)
      - Fall River (Box 10)
        Aerial photographs
      - Lawrence (Box 10)
      - Lynn, 1949 (Box 10)
        State housing project
      - North Adams (Box 10)
      - Norwood (Box 10)
      - Paxton (Box 10)
      - Quinby (Box 10)
      - Wellesley (Box 10)
      - Worcester (Box 10)
      - Miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 10)
    - Cambridge Planning Board
      1944-1953: Member. 1948: Secretary. 1948: Chairman
      - Correspondence, 1945-1953 (Box 11)
        Regarding appointments
      - Notebook I, 1945-1953 (Box 11)
        Legal matters, meetings, program, and annual reports (drafts)
      - Notebook II, 1945-1953 (Box 11)
        Public hearings
      - Notebook III, 1945-1953 (Box 11)
        Housing
      - Notebook IV, 1945-1953 (Box 11)
        Traffic, transit, recreation, miscellaneous
      - Pamphlets, 1945-1953 (Box 11)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1945-1953 (Box 11)
      - City of Cambridge Annual Reports, 1943, 1945-1950 (Box 11)
  - National Resources Planning Board (and its predecessors)
    1933-1943: Consultant to New Hampshire. 1943-1948: Consultant to Rhode Island.
    Material specific to Hertzog in New Hampshire and Rhode Island is in appropriate boxes.
    - National Planning Board
      - Addresses (Box 12)
      - Circular letters (Box 12)
      - Pamphlets (Box 12)
      - Forms (Box 12)
      - Circulars (Box 12)
      - Memoranda (Box 12)
      - Press Releases (Box 12)
    - National Resources Board
      - Orders (Box 12)
      - Memoranda (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - National Resources Committee
      - Press Release (Box 12)
      - Bibliographies (Box 12)
      - Memoranda (Box 12)
      - Forms (Box 12)
    - National Resources Planning Board
      - Memoranda (Box 12)
      - Administrative orders (Box 12)
      - Miscellaneous orders (Box 12)
      - Press Releases (Box 12)
      - Weekly summary of federal legislation (Box 12)
      - Schedule of weekly meetings (Box 12)
      - Forms (Box 12)
      - Bulletins - A, B, C, L (Box 12)
      - Circulars - R (Box 12)
  - New Hampshire
    1933-1943: State Planning Consultant, National Resources Planning Board
    - Correspondence and financial files
      - General, 1932-1947 (Box 13)
      - Works Progress Administration, 1935-1938 (Box 13)
      - New Hampshire Staff (Box 13)
      - Transportation requests (Box 13)
      - Accounts, 1934-1940 (Box 13)
      - Establishing of State Planning Board funds, 1933 (Box 13)
      - Consultants (Box 14)
    - General and Administrative Working Papers
      - Organization (Box 14)
      - Administration (Box 14)
      - Aviation (Box 14)
      - Forestry (Box 14)
      - Recreational Study (Box 14)
      - Survey of City Planning and Zoning (Box 14)
      - Drainage Basin Study (Box 14)
      - Possibility of Directing Settlement of Land under Private Ownership (Box 14)
      - New Hampshire State Departments (Box 16)
      - Federal Emergency Relief Administration - National Emergency Council (Box 16)
      - 2 Directories of Federal and State Departments and Agencies in New Hampshire, 1937, 1939 (Box 16)
      - Wolfsboro, 1931-1932 (Box 16)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 16)
    - Reports
      - New Hampshire Outline of State Plan, 1932 (Box 14)
      - New Hampshire State Planning and Development Commission, December, 1933 (Box 14)
      - Progress Report, May 15, 1934 (Box 14)
      - Report on Schools, May 25, 1934 (Box 14)
      - Supplementary Report, December 1933 - June 1934 (Box 14)
      - Suggestions for Specific Program of Planning Activity, June 13, 1934 (Box 14)
      - Report, July 17, 1934 (Box 14)
      - Suggestions for Securing Extension of Planning Assistance, July 30, 1934 (Box 14)
      - Digest of Preliminary Planning Report, October, 1934 (Box 14)
      - State Planning in New Hampshire, 1935 (Box 14)
      - Personnel, June 11, 1935 (Box 14)
      - Report, June 15, 1935 (Box 14)
      - Operations Program, September 1 - December 15, 1935 (Box 14)
      - Study of State Finance, 1900-1935 (Box 15)
      - Progress Report, June 15 - December 15, 1935 (Box 15)
      - Town Planning Project, 1935 (Box 15)
      - Report, July 1, 1936 (Box 15)
      - Progress Report, December 15, 1935-June 15, 1936 (Box 15)
      - State Planning Progress, 1933-1936 (Box 15)
      - Biennial Report, 1936-1937 (Box 15)
      - Merrimac River Basin, 1937 (Box 15)
      - Planning Division Program, 1937-1938 (Box 15)
      - Biennial Report, 1938-1939 (Box 15)
      - Biennial Report, 1940-1941 (Box 15)
      - Reports and typescripts (Box 15)
        Not Herzog's
      - Monthly Progress Reports (Box 15)
    - Publications and other press materials
      - Legislative material (Box 15)
      - Planning News (Box 15)
        2 issues
      - Press Dispatches (Box 15)
      - List of reports and publications (Box 15)
      - Town and City Zoning Primer (Box 15)
      - Water Bodies in New Hampshire (Box 15)
      - Extension of Public Ownership of Land (Box 15)
      - Public Passenger Carriers (Box 15)
      - Geology of the Franconia Quadrangle (Box 15)
      - New Hampshire Seacoast Regional Development Association, Seacoast Region of New Hampshire (Box 15)
      - New Hampshire, Dartmouth, Lake Sunapee Region, New London, N.H. (Box 15)
      - New Hampshire Lakes Region Association, The Lakes Region of New Hampshire (Box 15)
      - New Hampshire State Planning and Development Commission. New Hampshire: Land of Scenic Splendor, Concord, N.H. (Box 15)
      - Geology of the Littleton and Mossicauke Quadrangles (Box 15)
      - Proposed Improvement of Rye Harbor (Box 15)
      - New England Army Air Base (Box 15)
      - Urban Zoning, Part I (Box 15)
      - Communities, Settlements, and Neighborhood Centers (Box 15)
      - Marketing Forest Products (Box 15)
      - New Hampshire State Hospital (Box 15)
      - New Hampshire: A Historical Sketch (Box 15)
      - State Hospital Study (Box 15)
      - Geology of Mt. Chocorua Quadrangle (Box 15)
      - At Work - Men and Machines, 1939 (Box 15)
      - New Hampshire State Planning and Development Commission. Public Recreation Areas, Concord, N.H., 1938 (Box 15)
      - New Hampshire Lakes Region Association, Where To in the Lakes Region of Scenic New Hampshire, Plymouth, N.H., 1938 (Box 15)